Gail Jefferson papers, circa 1960s-2008
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Workshop Materials and Transcripts.
  - Transcripts. (Boxes 9-10, Box 8, Folders 1-5, Box 25, Folders 5, 8)
    Folder 5: Transcripts and paper “A Case of Transcriptional Stereotyping” related to a workshop at Odense, June 1994. Transcript documents a Danish speaker and German speaker conversing in English.
    Box 9
    Folders 1-4: Transcripts and notes of medical consultations.
    Folder 5: Dutch and English transcripts of 17-18 year olds doing homework.
    Folders 6-7: Counseling transcripts.
    Folder 8: Copies of Dutch transcript of Gesprek III and 5 letters from Iris Bogaers, University of Amsterdam, 1993.
    Box 10
    Folders 1-3, 5-9: Transcripts of medical consultations.
    Folder 4: Handwritten legal transcript.
    Folder 5: Data, notes, and transcripts for “going along with.”
    Folder 8: Feedback to students’ analysis of Coutchavlis transcript.
- Harvey Sacks' Lectures and Related Materials.
  BOX 11 TERMS
  Adjacency pairs: (broadly) some natural two-utterance sequences in which their parts properly go adjacently. A large number of them are known names, and given the names, the parts are relatively ordered and discriminatively related (from lecture 1 folder 1).
  BOX 13 TERMS
  ‘uh’: when someone initially responds with 'uh' before their actual answer to a question in conversation.
  BOX 14 TERMS
  Sequencing in conversation: aims to lay out some of the ways that the discoverable aspects of single utterances turn out to be handle-able by reference to sequencing considerations. Examines how sequencing considerations turn out to be implicative of what happens in a given utterance (Sacks).
  - Harvey Sacks' lectures. (Box 11, Folders 1-7, Box 20, Folders 6, 8-12, Box 21, Folders 1, 5, Box 4, Folder 7)
    Folder 7: Transcripts of 4 of Harvey Sacks’ lectures on greetings which includes larger collection of his lecture “Greetings Bypass.”
    Box 11
    Folder 1: Six original chapters for Sacks' Lectures on Conversation from Spring of 1972, edited by Jefferson. Lectures focus on ‘adjacency pairs.’
    Folder 2: Sixteen original chapters for Sacks' Lectures on Conversation from Fall of 1971, edited by Jefferson. Lectures focus on phenomenon of storytelling in conversation.
    Folder 3: Thirteen original chapters for Sacks' Lectures on Conversation from Spring 1971, edited by Jefferson. Lectures focus on conversation broadly.
    Folder 4: Three original chapters for Sacks' Lectures on Conversation from Winter of 1971, edited by Jefferson. Lectures focus on conversation broadly.
    Folder 5: Four original chapters for Sacks' Lectures on Conversation from Winter of 1970, edited by Jefferson. Lectures focus on overall structural organization of conversation.
    Folder 6: Eight original chapters for Sacks' Lectures on Conversation from Spring 1970, edited by Jefferson. Lectures focus on storytelling in conversation.
    Folder 7: Nine original chapters for Sacks’ Lectures on Conversation from Winter of 1969, edited by Jefferson. Lectures focus broadly on the makings of conversation.
    Box 20
    Folder 6: Manuscripts of selected Sacks lectures including letters and attached lecture –of “Ordinary People” from “Phillip” of the Centre for Socio-Legal Studies at Oxford.
    Folder 8: Sacks lectures and articles including “You Want to Find Out if Anybody Really Does Care,” “Remarks on Memory,” and “Some Considerations of a Story Told in Ordinary Conversation.”
    Folder 9: Transcription of Sacks’ lecture “Sacks: Ann Arbor Lecture 2.”
    Folder 10: Transcripts of Sacks’ lectures from 1961. Folder includes conversation between Sacks and Harold Garfinkel “New version of the problem of order” and Sacks’ presentation at the Ethnomethodology Conference, June 1962.
    Folder 11: Bound collection “Sacks Lectures: Fall, 1964. Retranscribed and New Transcripts.”
    Folder 12: Two copies of "Sacks Lectures: Fall 1964."
    Box 21
    Folder 1: Sacks lectures from 1972. Folder includes 1962 lecture “Localizing the World.”
    Folder 5: Sacks lectures from 1964-1965 including “Everyone Has to Lie.”
  - Related materials. (Boxes 12-15, Box 22, Folder 5, Box 20, Folders 1-5, 7, Box 21, Folders 2-4)
    Box 12
    Folder 1: Handwritten/draft reference lists and index list for Volume I of Jefferson’s book Harvey Sacks: Lectures, 1964-1965.
    Folder 2: Receipts and various loose sheets related to accountancy for Harvey Sacks: Lectures, 1964-1965.
    Folder 3: Complete indexes for both Volume I and II for Harvey Sacks: Lectures, 1964-1965.
    Folder 4: Internet sources for Harvey Sacks: Lectures, 1964-1965. Folder 5: Published reviews of Harvey Sacks: Lectures, 1964-1965.
    Folder 6: Revisions for final copy of Harvey Sacks: Lectures, 1964-1965.
    Folder 7: Six original chapters for Sacks’ Lectures on Conversation from Fall of 1968, edited by Jefferson. Lectures focus on sequential organization of conversation.
    Folder 8: Six original chapters for Sacks’ Lectures on Conversation from Spring of 1968, edited by Jefferson. Lectures focus on topic in conversation.
    Folder 9: Revisions for Volume I of Harvey Sacks: Lectures, 1964-1965.
    Box 13
    Folder 1: Transcripts of Sacks’ lectures from Fall of 1964.
    Folder 2: Copies of transcripts of Sacks’ lectures from Fall of 1964.
    Folder 3: Collections of corrections and notes. Folder 4: Materials related to publishers of Sacks’ book Lectures on Conversation, edited by Jefferson.
    Box 14
    Folders 1-2: Transcripts of Sacks’ Lectures from Spring of 1966, edited by Jefferson. Lectures mainly focus on a group therapy session for teenagers.
    Folders 3-5: Transcripts of Sacks’ Lectures from Spring of 1967, edited by Jefferson. Folder 3 lectures mainly focus on the consideration of “everyone has to lie” and “we” in conversation, folder 4 lectures focus on sequencing, and folder 5 lectures focus on multi-party conversations and consideration of a topic.
    Box 15
    Folder 1: Transcripts of Sacks’ Lectures from Fall of 1965, edited by Jefferson. Lectures focus on a group therapy session for teenagers.
    Folder 2: Materials from Blackwell Publishers for a proposed shorter volume of key readings of lectures.
    Folder 3: Materials related to Human Studies Special Issue of Sacks’ lectures.
    Folder 4: Copies of chapters from 1964-1965 edited by Jefferson for Blackwell book of selected readings from the Harvey Sacks: Lectures, 1964-1965.
    Folder 5: Complete proofs for Sacks’ selected readings book.
    Folder 1: Draft of Sacks’ paper “On Some Formal Properties of Children’s Games.”
    Folder 2: Extract from article “Intimates” by Paul Valery.
    Folder 3: Sacks’ handouts.
    Folder 4: Assorted collection of Sacks’ notes regarding various matters such as questions, children’s games, and categories.
    Folder 5: Chapter on sequential organization in conversation.
    Folder 7: Articles from Michael Moerman and Sacks.
    Folder 2: Sacks’ contributions to data sessions from Summer 1972.
    Folder 3: Bound collection titled “Sacks Worktapes,” transcribed data sessions at UCLA that include Frankel, Jefferson, Moerman, Pomerantz, Sacks, and Schegloff.
    Folder 4: Book on “Aspects of Sequential Organization.”
    Folder 5: Copy of Schegloff Article “On Sacks on Weber on Ancient Judaism,” 1999. Folder includes letters from Paul Drew.
- Transcripts, Talks, and Collections.
  BOX 16 TERMS
  Latency: delay/silence before a transfer of information.
  Stolen Jokes: Joke-teller displays recipient-ship of the steal or joke-teller dis-attends the steal (Jefferson).
  Pursuit tags: Relates to (1981) "The abominable 'ne?' An exploration of post-response pursuit of response." In P. Shroder (Hrsg.) Sprache der gegenwaart (pp.53-88).
  - Transcripts. (Box 16, Folders 1-4, 7, 10, Box 28, Folders 1-2, Box 22, Folders 3-4, Box 17, Folder 1, 6)
    Box 16
    Folder 1: Los Angeles Police Department (L.A.P.D.) transcripts.
    Folder 2: Transcriptions of speeches, letters, and interactions. This folder includes Richard Nixon's November 5, 1962 campaign speech for California Governor.
    Folder 3: Notes and transcripts for Jefferson’s talk “Some Notes on Behaviors of First- and Second-Person Reference in Overlap,” Katholieke Hogeschool Tilburg, June 1983.
    Folder 4: Copy of “Issues in the Transcription of Naturally-Occurring Talk: Caricature versus Capturing Pronunciational Particulars” with an appended glossary of transcript symbols.
    Folder 7: Data, transcripts, notes, and notices for Working Conference on Conversation Analysis, Human Interaction and Ethnomethodology, University of South Carolina, April 1980.
    Folder 10: Emanuel Schegloff's transcription critiques of a paper co-authored by Jefferson.
    Folder 1: Handwritten and typed transcripts.
    Folder 6: J.G. transcripts.
    Folders 3-4:Transcripts of doctor and patient interaction.
    Box 28
    Folder 1: Transcripts and notes on overlap including “Cancer on the Presidency” about President Richard Nixon.
    Folder 2: Heritage transcripts. Folder also contains Sacks’ “Notes on Methodology” and newspaper clippings.
  - Talks. (Box 16, Folders 11, 13)
    Folder 11: A talk on the organization of laughter.
    Folder 13: Drafts of Jefferson and Schegloff talk “Sketch: Some Orderly Aspects of Overlap in Natural Conversation” and collections on overlap in conversation.
  - Collections. (Box 16, Folders 6, 8-9, 12, Box 19, Folders 1-4)
    Folder 6: Collection of various exercises including handouts on latency.
    Folder 8: UCLA/UCI Seminars including collection of Stolen Jokes.
    Folder 9: A collection of transcripts including that of a Hell’s Angels interview tape.
    Folder 12: Collection of pursuit tags.
    Box 19
    Folders 1-4: Organized collection of “no” responses to questions. Folder 4 includes Harrie Mazeland draft of “Some notes on variance in the uses of minimal response tokens in medical consultations” and notes from Sacks lectures relating to Mazeland paper.
- Project Proposals and Reports.
  - Project proposals. (Box 16, Folder 5, Box 17, Folder 3)
    Folder 5: Research proposal for a two-year study of overlapping talk.
    Folder 3: Proposed project on error correction with Paul Drew and Tony Wootton.
  - Reports. (Box 22, Folder 2, Box 17, Folders 4, 7-9)
    Folder 4: Application and progress report for study of correction as it occurs in ordinary conversation.
    Folder 7: Final report for Social Science Research Council (SSRC) funded project “A Preliminary Exploration of Shift-Implicative Recipiency in the Articulation of Topic.”
    Folder 8: Final Report for SSRC funded project “The Analysis of Conversations in which ‘Troubles’ and ‘Anxieties’ are Expressed.”
    Folder 9: Original final report for SSRC funded project “A Preliminary Exploration of Shift-Implicative Recipiency in the Articulation of Topic.”
    Folder 2: Report based on the Warren Commission investigation of the assassination of John F. Kennedy.
- "At first I thought" Materials.
  Materials related to Jefferson's “'At First I Thought': A Normalising Device for Extraordinary Events” paper.
  - Talk, paper, and notes. (Box 18, Folders 1-3)
    Folder 1: Script of talk “At first I thought” and related newspaper clippings.
    Folder 2: A copy and versions of paper “At first I thought” given at the Temple University Conference on Discourse, March 1985.
    Folder 3: Early lecture notes on “At first I thought.”
  - Research materials. (Box 18, Folders 4-5)
    Folder 4: A mix of collections, transcripts, and notes including a collection of “I will” as a response.
    Folder 5: Copies of papers by various authors in conversation analysis including John Heritage, Christian Heath, and Charles Goodwin.
- Latency and Poetics Materials.
  - Collections. (Box 23, Folders 1-3, 6, Box 28, Folders 3-10, Box 29, Folders 1-2)
    Box 23
    Folders 1-3: Collections of the latency phenomenon in turn-taking.
    Folder 6: Collections of data for Poetics paper.
    Folder 3: Collections of Post-Silence Latency.
    Folder 4: Collection of Latency Phenomenon.
    Folder 5: Collection of doctor emergency calls, includes an attached note from Paul Drew.
    Folder 6: Collection of J10 data.
    Folder 7: Collection of Post-Silence Successive Onsets.
    Folders 8-9: Collection of Post-Silence Simultaneous Starts. Folder 10: ‘Disaffiliative’ Interaction and Latency: Post a Silence collection and handwritten Schenkein transcripts.
    Folders 1-2: Collection of post-silence latency.
  - Drafts. (Box 23, Folders 4-5)
    Folder 4: Draft versions and editorial materials related for “On the Poetics of Ordinary Conversation.”
    Folder 5: Collections, lecture notes, and drafts for Poetics paper. Folder includes Jefferson paper “Sometimes A Cigar is Just a Cigar: An Investigation of Some In-Speech Errors.”
- Poetics Paper and Standard Max Materials.
  BOX 27 TERMS
  Innocuous and Problematic Standard Max: silences in talk.
  - Poetics paper. (Box 27, Folder 1)
    Folder 1: Drafts of “On the Poetics of Ordinary Talk.”
  - Standard Max materials. (Box 27, Folders 2-10, Box 25, Folder 10)
    Folder 10: Papers by other authors such as B. Butterworth and Robert E. Kraut regarding silences in talk.
    Box 27
    Folder 2: Handwritten notes mostly in Dutch.
    Folder 3: Collections of Innocuous and Problematic Standard Max.
    Folder 4: Tallies of silences over 0.9 seconds.
    Folder 5: Collection of tallies and data for Standard Maximum.
    Folder 6: Collection of standoff silences.
    Folder 7: Paper “Preliminary Notes on a Possible Metric which Provides for a ‘Standard Maximum’ Silence of Approximately One Second in Conversation,” University of York, 1983.
    Folder 8: Handouts and draft paper for Standard Maximum York talk.
    Folder 9: Reference list for Het Biologisch-Muzisch Ritme.
    Folder 10: Collection of Standard Maximum Silences.
- Audiovisual Materials.
  SERIES CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials in this collection will require assessment and possible digitization for safe access. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
  Boxes 30-36 contain 218 audio cassettes and 2 VHS recordings.
  These materials include audio cassette and VHS recordings of interviews used as raw material in the creation of data collection transcriptions for Conversation Analysis.
  - Audio cassettes. (Boxes 30-36)
    BOXES CONTAIN AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials in this collection will require assessment and possible digitization for safe access. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
    The following boxes contain recordings of conversations and interviews used for transcription and analysis:
    Box 30 contains 44 audio cassettes.
    Box 31 contains 45 audio cassettes.
    Box 32 contains 45 audio cassettes.
    Box 33 contains 38 audio cassettes and 2 VHS tapes.
    Box 34 contains 45 audio cassettes.
    Box 35 contains 46 audio cassettes.
    Box 36 contains 18 audio cassettes.
  - VHS cassettes. (Box 33)
    BOX CONTAINS AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials in this collection will require assessment and possible digitization for safe access. All requests to access special collections material must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
    Box 33 contains 2 VHS cassettes. One is labeled "Copy for GJ" and the other is labeled with the following:
    1) 112 [and] 353-15.1.01
    2) 109 [and] 315-27.10.00
    3) 347 [and] 102-6.12.00